Guide to the Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County Records, 1968 AIS.1968.22
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County Records
1968
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County (Pa.)
AIS.1968.22
0.42 Linear Feet (1 box)
The records of the Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County consist of news releases, brochures, newspaper clippings, correspondence, campaign materials, and convention and platform materials for the year 1968.
History
The Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County was organized to support the candidacy of Dick Gregory and Mark Lane on an independent party ticket in the Presidential campaign of 1968.
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County consist of news releases, brochures, newspaper clippings, correspondence, campaign materials, and convention and platform materials for the year 1968. Additional records include materials for the Pennsylvania Electoral Conference, which saw the organization of Pennsylvanians for a Peace and Freedom ticket, photographs, successor to the Pennsylvanians for a Peace and Freedom ticket, and miscellaneous material from other peace and freedom groups in Allegheny County. All records are from the year 1968.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was a gift of Walter Tillow on December 12, 1968.
Previous Citation
Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County Records, 1968, AIS.1968.22, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County -- Political activity; African American political activists -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Political parties -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Presidents -- United States -- Elections; Politics; Social action; Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County (Pa.); Peace and Freedom Party (U.S.); Pennsylvania Electoral Conference, 1968; Pennsylvanians for a Peace and Freedom Ticket
- Pennsylvania Electoral Conference, 1968; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contans the materials for the call to Convention which saw the organization of Pennsylvanians for a Peace and Freedom ticket. The electoral conference took place in Harrisburg.
  - PA Electoral Conference, January 13-14, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Pennsylvanians for a Peace and Freedom ticket, 1968; II.
  This series contains materials regarding the support of the Peace and Freedom ticket. Included are correspondence, financial records, publicity, and miscellaneous materials.
  - General correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Form letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bills, invoices, and receipts (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Check book, deposit slips (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - News releases (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brochures and broadcasts (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Peace and Freedom Party of Allegheny County, 1968; III.
  Series III contains material regarding the Party chairman Walter Tillow, business papers, financial records, legal papers, selected copies of Pittsburgh Peace and Freedom News, and political papers.
  - Walter Tillow correspondence, telegrams, and memorandum (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Agreement for political broadcasts (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lease to Peace and Freedom Office (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Deposit slips (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Search warrant for campaign item resembling one dollar U.S. Federal Reserve Note (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pittsburgh Peace and Freedom News, January, February-March, and October issues (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  - Nomination papers (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Campaign material (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Peace and Freedom Party (National), 1968; IV.
  Series IV contains material regarding the National Peace and Freedom Party, including policies, guidelines, and the National Convention.
  - Organizing Committee Policy Guidelines (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - National Convention Committee (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - New York Convention (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Platform (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Guidelines for functioning of Local Freedom and Peace Clubs (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Peace and Freedom Party Movement Organizations, 1968; V.
  Series V contains material regarding Peace and Freedom Party Movement Organizations from across the United States.
  - Black Panther Party for Self-Defense; Ministry of Information (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Committee for a Write-in-vote for Dick Gregory, Berkeley, CA (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dick Gregory for President Committee, Berkeley, CA (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Freedom and Peace Party, New York (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Liberation News Service (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Michigan Democrats Against Racism (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - National Gregory for President Committee (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - New Party Organizing Committee, New York (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Peace and Freedom Organizing Committee materials from various cities in United States (Box 1, Folder 35-40)
  - Sanity Now, La Puenta, CA (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Virginia Peace and Freedom Organizing Committee, Hampton, VA (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Washington Peace and Freedom Party, Seattle, WA (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - West Philadelphia Club of the Peace and Freedom Party (Box 1, Folder 44)